Fate has found its hero.
K-19: The Widowmaker is a drama, history, thriller
film directed by Kathryn Bigelow.
When Russia's first nuclear submarine malfunctions on its maiden voyage, the
crew must race to save the ship and prevent a nuclear disaster.
Alexei Vostrikov, played by Harrison Ford.
Mikhail Polenin, played by Liam Neeson.
Vadim Radtchinko, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
Marshal Zelentsov, played by Joss Ackland.
Admiral Bratyeev, played by John Shrapnel.
Dr. Savran, played by Donald Sumpter.
K-19: The Widowmaker is a 2002 historical submarine film directed and
produced by Kathryn Bigelow, and produced by Edward S.
Feldman, Sigurjon Sighvatsson, Christine Whitaker and
Matthias Deyle with screenplay by Christopher Kyle.
An international co-production of the United States, United Kingdom, Germany and Canada, the film
takes place in 1961 and focuses its story on the Soviet Hotel-class submarine K-19.
The film stars Harrison Ford and Liam Neeson alongside Peter Sarsgaard, Donald Sumpter,
Christian Camargo, Michael Gladis and John Shrapnel in supporting roles.
K-19: The Widowmaker was released by Paramount Pictures in the United States on July 19, 2002,
in Germany on September 5, 2002, and in the United Kingdom on October 25, 2002.
The film received mixed reviews upon release, with critics praising the
performances and dramatic atmosphere, but criticizing the screenplay.
The film was also a box-office bomb, grossing only $65.7
million worldwide on a budget of $90 million.
The film explores themes of submarine, cold war, soviet
union, based on true story, north atlantic.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending and emotional.